compassion.com 2019-05-13

# Privacy and Conditions of Use - Compassion International

Manage Your Email and Text Subscriptions

You may manage your email and text preferences in My Account or call us at   
(800) 336-7676. To discontinue SMS text messages from Compassion International, text **STOP** to **97646**. 

View subscription or transactional SMS terms and conditions.

**Compassion International Privacy Statement**

Compassion International is committed to respecting your privacy and security. We provide this Privacy Statement to make you aware of our privacy policy and security practices, and to inform you about the way your information is collected and used. To make this notice easy to find, we make it available on our homepage and from the bottom of every Compassion International web page. Once you choose to provide us personally identifiable information (any information by which you can be identified) either online or offline, you can be assured that it will only be used to support your relationship with Compassion International.

**Information Collected**

In your relationship with Compassion International, you can become a sponsor, make donations, request materials or subscribe to magazines, emails or SMS text messages. The types of personal information we may collect include name, contact and billing information, transaction and payment information. As you write letters to children, those messages will be stored digitally in our systems. Finally if you apply for a job, all related application information will be collected and stored. In order to tailor our subsequent communications to you and continuously improve our services, we may also ask you to provide us with information regarding your personal or professional interests, demographics, experiences as a sponsor, and contact preferences.

**Use and Disclosure of Information**

Compassion International uses your information to understand your needs and provide you with better service. Specifically, we use your information to help you complete a transaction, communicate back to you, update you on your sponsored child and special events, and to personalize our services and communications with you. Credit card and/or checking account information is used only for payment processing and is not retained for other purposes. From time to time, we may also use your information to contact you for market research or provide you with information we think would be of particular interest. At a minimum, we will always give you the opportunity to opt out or decline Compassion marketing or market research contact. We will also follow local requirements, such as allowing you to opt in before receiving unsolicited contact, where applicable. Data collected may also be combined with information you provide when you register as a Compassion sponsor. Furthermore, we use 3rd-party demographic data (such as age, gender and interests) to better understand how our website is used and to make improvements in usability.

**Who we share it with**

It is Compassion International’s policy to ensure that personal data is not used or disclosed except as necessary to provide services, to protect the confidentiality or security of personal data or as otherwise permitted by law. Compassion International does not rent, sell, or lease personal data with others. However, in those situations where we retain third parties to perform processing tasks or other activities, and transfers personal data to those partners or to any of our international offices, we require that these groups agree to provide at least an equivalent level of protection as provided by Compassion International.

**Links to Other Resources**

Our web sites may contain links to other online resources. We provide the links for your convenience, but we do not review, control, or monitor the privacy practices of online resources operated by others. This Privacy Statement does not apply to any other online resources where a link to this Privacy Statement does not appear. We are not responsible for the performance of sites operated by third parties or for your business dealings with them. Therefore, whenever you leave this Web Site we recommend that you review each site's privacy practices and make your own conclusions regarding the adequacy of these practices.

**Choice**

Compassion International will not use or share the personally identifiable information you provide to us in ways unrelated to the ones described above without first letting you know and offering you a choice. As previously stated, you may let us know if you do not wish to receive unsolicited direct marketing materials from us, and we will do everything we can to honor such requests.

**Accuracy**

Compassion International takes reasonable steps to ensure that personal data is reliable, accurate, and complete. The steps we take to ensure data integrity are made in light of the purposes for which the Personal Data is used. It is the policy of Compassion International to ensure that all Personal Data is maintained only as long as necessary or as otherwise permitted by law.

**Access**

We will make every effort to provide you with online access to your sponsor registration data so that you may update or correct your information at the Compassion International site or service where it was submitted. To review or correct your personal information offline contact us at (800) 336-7676, Monday through Friday, 7 a.m. to 5:30 p.m. MT. To protect your privacy and security, we will also take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting you access or enabling you to make corrections. It is the policy of Compassion International to ensure that all personal data is maintained only as long as necessary or as otherwise permitted by law.

**Security**

Compassion International is committed to ensuring the security of your information. We have implemented reasonable electronic, physical and procedural safeguards designed to help protect against the loss, unauthorized access or disclosure, alteration or destruction of the information under our control. We use encryption systems, when collecting or transferring sensitive data such as credit card information. Certain features of our Web Sites may require you to use an access code, password or similar unique identifier. You are responsible for protecting the secrecy of your account information. Although we strive to protect your personal information, no data transmission over the Internet is completely secure. There is some risk associated with any data transmission, including the risk that personal information may be intercepted in transit. If a breach of your personal information occurs we will provide a notification within a timeframe and by a manner permitted by your local jurisdiction.

**Consent to Transfer**

This Web Site is operated in the United States. If you are located in the European Union, Canada or elsewhere outside of the United States, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to the United States. By using the Web Site or providing us with your information, you consent to this transfer.

**Conditions of Use**

Compassion International, Inc. provides these services described to you subject to the conditions contained within this Privacy Statement. If you visit our website you accept these conditions. Please read them carefully. In addition, when you use any current or future Compassion International, Inc. website, service or visit any entity referenced by Compassion International, Inc., in its website, you also will be subject to the guidelines and conditions applicable to any such entity.

**Copyright**

All content included on this site, such as text, graphics, logos, photographs, button icons, images, audio clips, digital downloads, data compilations, and software, is the sole and exclusive property of Compassion International, Inc. or its content suppliers and is protected by United States and international copyright laws. The compilation of all content on this site is the exclusive property of Compassion International, Inc. and protected by U.S. and international copyright laws.

**Trademarks**

Compassion International, Inc.'s trade names, trademarks, trade dress, and service marks, including those marks indicated on our website are the sole and exclusive property of Compassion International, Inc., including, without limitation, designs, logos, page headers, button icons and scripts ("Marks"). Compassion International, Inc.'s Marks and trade dress may not be used in connection in any way not expressly authorized in writing by the Compassion International, Inc. or in any manner that is likely to cause confusion among the public, or in any manner that disparages or discredits Compassion International, Inc. All other trademarks not owned by Compassion International, Inc. that appear on this site are the property of their respective owners.

**License and Site Access**

Compassion International, Inc. grants you a limited, nonexclusive, nontransferable, and revocable license to access and make personal use of this site and not to download or modify it, or any portion of it, except with express written consent of the Compassion International, Inc. This license does not include any resale or commercial use of this site or its contents; any collection and use of any information, images, content or photographs or any derivative use of this site or its contents; any downloading or copying of information for the benefit of another; or any use of data mining, robots, or similar data gathering and extraction tools. This site or any portion of this site may not be reproduced, duplicated, copied, sold, resold, visited, or otherwise exploited for any commercial purpose without express written consent of Compassion International, Inc. You may not frame or utilize framing techniques to enclose any Marks, photographs, content or other proprietary information (including images, text, page layout, or form) of Compassion International, Inc.'s website without express written consent. You may not use any meta tags or any other "hidden text" utilizing Compassion International, Inc.'s website name or Marks without the express written consent of Compassion International, Inc. Any unauthorized use terminates the permission or license granted by Compassion International, Inc., to access this site. DISCLAIMER OF WARRANTIES AND LIMITATION OF LIABILITY THIS SITE IS PROVIDED BY COMPASSION INTERNATIONAL, INC. ON AN "AS IS" AND "AS AVAILABLE" BASIS. COMPASSION INTERNATIONAL, INC. MAKES NO REPRESENTATIONS OR WARRANTIES OF ANY KIND, EXPRESS OR IMPLIED, AS TO THE OPERATION OF THIS SITE OR THE INFORMATION, CONTENT OR MATERIALS INCLUDED ON THIS SITE. YOU EXPRESSLY AGREE THAT YOUR USE OF THIS SITE IS AT YOUR SOLE RISK. COMPASSION INTERNATIONAL DOES NOT WARRANT THAT THIS SITE, ITS SERVERS, OR E-MAIL SENT FROM THE COMPASSION INTERNATIONAL WEBSITE ARE FREE OF VIRUSES OR OTHER HARMFUL COMPONENTS. COMPASSION INTERNATIONAL, INC. WILL NOT BE LIABLE FOR ANY DAMAGES OF ANY KIND ARISING FROM THE USE OF THIS SITE, INCLUDING, BUT NOT LIMITED TO, INDIRECT, INCIDENTAL, PUNITIVE, AND CONSEQUENTIAL DAMAGES.

**Site policies, modification, and severability**

Compassion International, Inc., reserves the right to make changes to this site, policies, and these Conditions of Use at any time. If any of these conditions shall be deemed invalid, void, or for any reason unenforceable, that condition shall be deemed severable and shall not affect the validity and enforceability of any remaining condition.

**Are cookies used?**

Cookies are used to determine the success of Compassion's website and marketing campaigns. This allows us to be good stewards with the donations that are given to us to determine our online effectiveness, which also helps keep our expenses low.

In addition to cookies, we use other technologies, including pixel tags, to gather information on how our users interact with our website and to help us efficiently monitor our website and marketing campaigns. These technologies, for example, show us popular pages, conversion rates, click-throughs and other information that can be used to improve our website. We also occasionally share select non-personal information with trusted third parties. Compassion and its third party vendors use pixel tags to track and analyze non-personally identifiable usage information to compile statistical traffic analysis or usage patterns. Third-party cookies may also be used to inform, optimize and serve Compassion ads on other websites based on your visits to Compassion websites.

**What is a cookie?**

A cookie is a series of data characters that, when programmed into a website, is placed by the web server into the browser's application folder on your computer. Once placed onto your machine, the cookie will allow the website to "recognize" you as a unique individual. Cookies do not collect data from the end user's hard drive.

**Can cookies be removed from my hard drive?**

Yes, cookies can be removed from your hard drive. Also, depending on what type of web browser and what browser version you are using, you may be able to change the properties on your cookie file so that cookies are not used or saved. Please check with your browser provider for more information on removing cookies.

Learn more about Compassion's commitment to child protection.

_Updated May 2017_
